A Tragedy of the Great War
Archangel is a war, romance, drama film directed by Guy Maddin.
At the height of the October Revolution during the 1919 allied intervention in
Arkhangelsk, the exploits of one-legged Canadian soldier Lt.
John Boles are told, after he is taken in from the cold by a dysfunctional
Russian family and mistakes a local woman for his presumed dead lover.
Jannings, played by Michael Gottli.
Geza, played by David Falkenburg.
Doctor, played by Michael O'Sullivan.
Baba, played by Margaret Anne MacLeod.
Philbin, played by Ari Cohen.
Danchuk, played by Sarah Neville.
Archangel is a 1990 comedy-drama film directed by Guy Maddin.
The film fictionalizes, in a general sense, historical conflict related to the Bolshevik Revolution occurring in
the Arkhangelsk (Archangel) region of Russia, a basic concept presented to Maddin by John Harvie.
The film marks Maddin's first formal collaboration
with co-screenwriter George Toles.
Maddin shot Archangel in black and white, on 16
mm film, on a budget of $430,000.
Maddin modeled the film on the style of a part-talkie, an early cinema genre.
The "basic situation" of the film's story was
"suggested by Henry Green's 1946 novel Back."
The film explores themes of amnesia, surrealism,
black and white, silent film, dreamlike.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and mind_bending.